tradewindsnews.com 2017-06-06

# TradeWinds

### Cookie Policy

TradeWinds uses information files (cookies) to customise content and develop our digital publication and services (hereafter referred to as “digital solutions”).  Information files or cookies are small data or text files which a website may store on your computer or mobile device when you visit a site or page. The cookie will help the website, or another website, to recognise your device, choices and preferences the next time you visit. Web beacons or other similar files can also do the same thing. We use the term cookies when referring to all files that collect information in this way.

We use cookies for many purposes, primarily for analysis, but also in connection with marketing to customise content and advertising optimally. Examples are:

General statistics for our digital solutions and their performance

Manage User-ids and preferences

Remember-me functionality for log-in

Manage access control for various products and services

Improve technical performance and quality on our sites

We use several types of cookies:

### **Session-based cookies**

Session based cookies are automatically deleted when you close your browser. We use these to register when you are online on our digital solutions, and how you navigate, for instance while using MyTradeWinds pages. 

### **Fixed cookies**

These cookies are used to collect information on authentication and preferences. They aren’t deleted when you exit the browser but on a later designated date, or when you delete them yourself. By using these cookies we optimise the performance of our services and can make sure your log-in details and preferences are remembered the next time you log on. We also use them to track your use of the website and to remind you to update your subscription details from time to time.

### **Third-party cookies**

We may also use third-party cookies that could be both session-based or fixed. They are typically used in advertisements on our digital solutions. If you click on links provided by a third party, terms and conditions for these third-party suppliers apply, including their cookie policies. We allow advertisers to place such cookies on their advertisements to enable them to monitor the efficiency of their advertising. This is limited to anonymous data and cannot be traced back to you as a person. 

Disabling cookies

You may at any point disable cookies in the settings or internet options menu in your browser. There are also tools that can monitor and give you the overview of which cookies are used on the web pages you visit. To learn more, see for instance [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/)  or [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

Cookies are essential to the administration of our subscriber-based services. If you do disable our cookies you will find that certain sections of our website do not work. For example, you will have difficulties logging in or viewing articles.

If you require further information, please contact us at [webmaster@tradewindsnews.com](mailto:webmaster@tradewindsnews.com). 

### Privacy policy

_Updated 01.03.2016_

TradeWinds is committed to safeguarding the privacy of our users while providing a personalised and valuable service. We treat personal information in accordance with the Norwegian Personal Data Act and other current applicable legislation, and in compliance with European Convention of Human Rights Act article 8. This declaration explains which personal information we receive and collect when you use the digital publications and services provided by TradeWinds, and what we do to protect them. If you have any queries regarding the data processing and practices please contact us by email at [webmaster@tradewindsnews.com](mailto:webmaster@tradewindsnews.com).

Our sites contain links to third-party sites, which are not subject to this privacy policy. We recommend that you also read the privacy policy of any such sites that you visit.

We recommend that you familiarise yourself with this privacy policy statement. By using our publications and services (herewith called our “digital solutions”) you consent with our treatment of personal information in accordance with this declaration and within the framework of current legislation.

**Data controller**

TradeWinds is responsible for the treatment of personal information data in connection with digital solutions provided by TradeWinds.

### **Personal information**

**Information provided by you**

TradeWinds collects and treats personally identifiable information from registration forms, purchases and details provided off- and online such as:

Name  
Job title  
Company name  
Company address, phone and fax number  
Home address and phone number  
Mobile telephone number  
E-mail address  
Payment details such as credit card information

**Information collected from usage**

When you use our digital solutions TradeWinds will register your activity with the help of various tools. Please see our cookie policy for more information. We will also collect information from the device you are using while visiting our digital solutions, for example IP-address, operative systems, browsers and networks.

We also collect information on usage and traffic, for example log-in information, readership and navigation patterns, number of impressions and users. Included in this is newsletter reception and readerhip, email clients, location and which articles you click on.  

If you are using location-based services, TradeWinds may collect and treat information about your location. We will actively seek your consent before we collect such information. You may at any time withdraw such consent in accordance with current legislation.   

### **Cookie information**

We use information files on our digital solutions, so-called “cookies”. For further information, please see [www.tradewindsnews.com/terms](http://www.tradewindsnews.com/terms/)

Please note that by using our digital solutions you accept our use of cookies. 

### **Our use of personal information**

We use your data to provide you with the services you have registered for and to communicate with you regarding these. Data is treated for purposes which include providing our users with a personalised service, processing orders, registrations and enquiries and providing you with information about products and services we offer.

TradeWinds will not share your data with third-party organisations.

We may contact you about specific recruitment opportunities if you register search criteria information on our recruitment sites.

Furthermore we may collect and treat data based on your usage to customise content and advertising based on behaviour and assumption of preferences, to analyse market trends, to improve our publications and services and to monitor compliance with our Terms and Conditions and Copyright Policy. 

### **User Profiles**

We also use aggregated information (individual users remain anonymous) to build up marketing profiles for strategic development, segmenting and advertising purposes.

The data we collect in this way helps us to identify usability issues, to improve the assistance and technical support we can provide to users, and is also used for aggregated and statistical reporting purposes.

### **Marketing**

We use personal information to provide you with information and to market publications and services you may be interested in, based on data you have registered yourself or we have collected through use of our digital solutions.

As a subscriber, trial subscriber or registered user of any of our services, including newsletters, you have consented to receiving electronic communication and marketing from us as a customer. We may then send you emails and text messages in compliance with current legislation, until you give notice that such communication is no longer welcome. You may at any time choose to opt out of such communications.     

If you haven’t registered as a user or customer of our products and services, we will only send you offers and information if you have expressively consented to this.

### **Disclosure of personal information**

We may also disclose your information to business partners and to third-party suppliers we engage to provide services which involve processing data on our behalf, other companies within the NHST Media Group or successors in title to our business. If we disclose data to third-party suppliers, we will secure that they treat the data in accordance with our privacy policy as well as current legislation. Furthermore, we may give third-party suppliers access to aggregated and anonymized data. We may also disclose data in accordance with properly executed court orders, or as otherwise required to do so by law.

### **Our treatment of data**

Only authorised personnel in TradeWinds or NHST Media Group will have access to personal information. Data is secured with access controls and passwords, and appropriate measures are in place to ensure data is protected against unlawful or accidental destruction and accidental loss.

Routines for internal control and information security are documented and revised annually to ensure compliance with current legislation.

Your personal information will only be stored as long as there is a factual and relevant need in compliance with this personal policy declaration and current legislation. When such need no longer exist, the data will be deleted or anonymised.

### **Your rights**

In accordance with the Norwegian Personal Data Act you have at all times the right to review the information we store about you. You have the right to amend or delete data at all times. 

### **Changes to this policy**

TradeWinds will revise this personal data protection declaration when the treatment of data or processes change. We will also revise it in accordance with changes in the relevant legislation and website. Changes are valid from the date published on the declaration. We will make important revisions visible but recommend that you read the privacy policy declaration on a regular basis when visiting our digital solutions. 

### **Enquiries**

For more information about our personal information policies, please[ contact us](http://www.tradewindsnews.com/contactus/).

### What is the difference between a Basic & Standard subscription, and how do I upgrade?

A Standard subscription includes access to the full archive, from 1990 to date. An upgrade is easily ordered from your My TradeWinds account. [Click here](http://www.tradewindsnews.com/mytw/) or simply contact your closest sales office.

**Standard**  
A Standard subscription includes the weekly hard copy newspaper delivered to your chosen address, as well as the quarterly magazine TW+. Full access to the news site and Apps (iOs and Android) with the digital versions of the printed editions is included. Standard package subscribers enjoy unrestricted access to the fully searchable, extensive archive section from 1990 to date. Plus RSS feed, daily Headline newsletter email and discounts on TradeWinds Events.

**Basic**  
A Basic subscription includes the weekly hard copy newspaper and quarterly magazine TW+. You also have access to the web site with news and reports from the last two weeks. Plus RSS feed, daily Headline newsletter email and the 2 most recent weekly E-paper editions. You may also download the digital versions of the print editions on your mobile device via our Apps (iOs or Android). Subscribers also enjoy discounts on delegate fees for TradeWinds Events.

### Is the digital edition included in my subscription?

As a subscriber to TradeWinds you have access to the weekly digital edition via an e-reader on the website, as well as through apps for mobile devices. The latest web news is also available via your tablet or smart phone. Simply [ download ](http://www.tradewindsnews.com/help/) the Apps in either App store or Google Play.

The apps are free to download and once logged in with your subscription details you may download any issue to read offline.

The latest issue is available Thursdays at 6pm GMT.

### Why can’t I log in?

Make sure you have typed in the correct userid and password.  If you have created a user account and can’t log in on My TradeWinds, try resetting the password by clicking [here](http://www.tradewindsnews.com/login/) and choose “Forgot your password?”

### Which browsers are recommended?

We recommend using the latest updated versions of browsers that follow web standards, such as: Internet Explorer, Chrome, Mozilla Firefox, Safari etc.

### Why can’t I access all areas of the site?

TradeWinds is a subscription based news service, and access to the site is provided via a userid and password. To register, please complete the order process. A few articles per day are open to the general public, these are marked by an open lock. TradeWinds Events, TradeWinds Jobs and general information pages are open to all.

Archived content, defined as web news older than 14 days and weekly editions more than 4 weeks old are included in the Standard subscription. If your current subscription is Basic, you can easily upgrade by contacting us via [email ](mailto:sales@tradewindsnews.com) or calling your nearest [ TradeWinds sales office](http://www.tradewindsnews.com/contactus/).

### Why can’t I access articles more than 14 days old? 

Archived content, defined as web news older than 14 days and weekly editions more than 4 weeks old are included in the Standard subscription. If your current subscription type is Basic, you can easily upgrade by contacting us via [ email](mailto:sales@tradewindsnews.com) or calling your nearest [TradeWinds sales office](http://www.tradewindsnews.com/contactus/).

### What does “you have exceeded the maximum number of users” message mean?

Please note that the number of licenses (or accesses) to www.tradewindsnews.com is limited to the number of subscriptions on your account. Your username and password are personal to you and may not be shared by anyone else when you have a single user license.

This message may also occur when you navigate using the back button in your browser. We recommend you return to the front page by clicking the TradeWinds logo or home button between reading each article.

In case someone else is logged in with your details or you receive the message in connection with using the back button, please log out and wait 30 minutes before you log in again. If the problem persists, please contact [TradeWinds customer service](http://www.tradewindsnews.com/mytw/contact/).

### What are the terms of my subscription?

**Rates and Payments**  
Prices are set by TradeWinds AS and displayed on the website and in the newspaper. We reserve the right to increase our subscription rates. Subscription rate increases are notified via the newspaper. Prices quoted include the paper copy and online access depending on your subscription level, as well as delivery charges. Local taxes may apply.

Payments are accepted by bank transfer or credit/debit card. We accept Visa, MasterCard or American Express. Bank details are provided on all our invoices, and a credit card form is available on page two of our invoices. We do not accept cheques. The subscriber may continue to receive reminders from TradeWinds until payment has been received.

**Credit Terms**  
Credit terms are 28 days from date of invoice. All invoices are sent out up to two months in advance prior to renewal or any new subscriptions setup at the next available date.

**Subscription Terms**  
All TradeWinds subscriptions are available on a yearly basis. All subscriptions are automatically renewed, unless we are advised otherwise.

As a subscriber you will receive letters and emails from TradeWinds. The content of the communication will be service messages, offers and newsletters with useful information regarding the subscription and TradeWinds products. TradeWinds will treat contact details with confidentiality and not share details with any third party supplier.

TradeWinds reserves the right to make changes in the product as well as terms and conditions. Major changes will be notified in the paper and/or via email.

**Login Details**  
Login details are sent to the subscriber only, unless prior permission has been given for login details and passwords to forwarded to a trusted individual. Your login is your email address. If you forget any of these details, please contact us via [My TradeWinds ](http://www.tradewindsnews.com/mytw/login/)or select “Forgot your password” on the login page. Otherwise, please contact your [nearest office ](http://www.tradewindsnews.com/contactus/)or [Customer Services](http://www.tradewindsnews.com/mytw/contact/).

**Number of Licences**  
Please note that the number of licenses (or accesses) to [www.tradewindsnews.com](http://www.tradewindsnews.com/) is limited to the number of subscriptions on your account and can only be used on a single device at any one time.. Your username and password are personal to you and may not be shared by anyone else when you have a single user license.

**Copyright policy/Editorial content**  
TradeWinds content is under strict copyright and TradeWinds holds exclusive rights to all material published in its channels. Any republication, redistribution or re-editing or other use of this material in any form, including by framing or similar means, or by electronic linking, is prohibited without the prior consent of TradeWinds. Requests to reproduce any material should be addressed to the Editor-in-Chief at [news@tradewindsnews.com](mailto:news@tradewindsnews.com).

**VAT**  
VAT may be charged according to local regulations. 25% VAT applies to digital subscriptions in Norway, and TradeWinds charges this to a portion of the subscription fee to cover the online content.

**Discounts**  
TradeWinds does not offer discounts on subscriptions. Students and retired professionals may qualify for a discount. Please contact your nearest sales office regarding this. TradeWinds does offer volume corporate agreements tailored to each customers’ needs, please inquire further about this with your [sales account manager](http://www.tradewindsnews.com/contactus/).

**Subscription Amendments**  
For any changes to your subscription, please contact us through[ My TradeWinds](http://www.tradewindsnews.com/mytw/login/), email [sales@tradewindsnews.com](mailto:sales@tradewindsnews.com) or contact your nearest [sales office](http://www.tradewindsnews.com/contactus/).

**Invoice Copies**  
If you require an invoice copy, please email [accounts@tradewindsnews.com](mailto:accounts@tradewindsnews.com) or contact your local [sales office](http://www.tradewindsnews.com/contactus/).

**Basic & Standard Subscriptions**  
A Basic subscription consists of the paper copy of the newspaper, with online access to the previous 14 days’ worth of articles. The Standard subscription is an upgrade from the Basic, which includes the archived material and gives subscribers access to any previous content since the launch of TradeWinds in 1990.

**Delivery**  
TradeWinds is distributed via first class mail, and subject to deadlines stated by the individual mail service companies globally. In many central shipping locations we offer hand delivery. If you do not receive your newspaper copy, please contact your local sales office as soon as possible.

New subscriptions and changes to distribution details can be received up until Wednesday morning at 10am GMT for that week’s Friday issue. TradeWinds is printed in the UK, and distribution is dependent on your location.

**Cancellations**  
All subscriptions are renewed unless notice is given. Cancellation is always required in writing either by letter or email. If a cancellation is received after the renewal  date, a balance invoice will be payable for the period used. We reserve the right to terminate the subscription at any time due to lack of payment.

### Which payment methods are accepted? 

Wire transfers and most major credit cards are accepted. Credit card payments are easily managed with your [My TradeWinds account](http://www.tradewindsnews.com/mytw/login/), but it is also possible to arrange via your regional [TradeWinds sales office](http://www.tradewindsnews.com/contactus/).

Please refer to the invoice or subscription number when paying by wire transfer. Bank account and swift codes can be found on the invoice. Bank drafts and personal cheques are not accepted. 

### Where can I find an invoice copy? 

Your My TradeWinds user account will display your current payment status and whether you have an outstanding invoice. To receive a pdf copy of the latest invoice, contact customer service by [clicking here ](http://www.tradewindsnews.com/mytw/contact/)or contact your closest [TradeWinds sales office](http://www.tradewindsnews.com/contactus/).

### Who qualifies for a discount?

Students and retired professionals may qualify for a discount. Please contact your nearest [sales office](http://tradewindsnews.com/contactus/).

### I haven’t received my paper, what should I do?

If you aren’t receiving the paper as normal, please contact [customer service ](http://www.tradewindsnews.com/mytw/contact/)either via email or calling your closest [sales office](http://www.tradewindsnews.com/contactus/). Delivery inquiries are highly prioritized. If you are receiving the paper via a local hand-delivery agent, you may also contact the distribution agent directly, see [www.tradewindsnews.com/subscribe/distribution/](http://www.tradewindsnews.com/subscribe/distribution/)

### How quickly will my subscription start? 

New subscriptions and changes to distribution details can be received up until Wednesday morning 10am GMT for that week’s Friday issue. TradeWinds is printed in UK and distribution time is dependent on your location.

### How can I change contact details, delivery and invoice address on my subscription?

This is easily done by using the service page on My TradeWinds. If you don’t have access you can contact us via [ email](mailto:sales@tradewindsnews.com) or call your nearest [sales office.](http://tradewindsnews.com/contactus/)

### How can I contact the editorial department?

Letters to the editor, press releases etc can be emailed to [letters@tradewindsnews.com](mailto:letters@tradewindsnews.com). Full contact list of the editorial staff can be found on [contact form](http://www.tradewindsnews.com/contactus).
